<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nature and Art</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nature and Art</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024, Beach Ogden.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bob Ross in Art History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bob-ross-in-art-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bob-ross-in-art-history/</guid>
      <description>There is one&#xA;Focus on https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lLWEXRAnQd0 and do a formal analysis&#xA;On the surface, yes, The Joy of Painting is designed so folks can dabble along from home. But it&amp;rsquo;s a rare fan who&amp;rsquo;s squeezed out a tube of Prussian Blue. Ross knew it. As he told the Orlando Sentinel in 1990: &amp;ldquo;The majority of our audience does not paint, has no desire to paint, will never paint.&amp;rdquo; Instead, the show&amp;rsquo;s appeal is more abstract.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landscape painting formal analysis.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/landscape-painting-formal-analysis./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/landscape-painting-formal-analysis./</guid>
      <description>Dividing the artwork into several levels:&#xA;Flat plain at the bottom with trees The bottom depicts a native american tribe (what tribe). All of the natives are engaged in immediate affairs with animals they hunted, fabrics, talking, or on horses, with the exception of two individuals by the lake, looking up at the vast peak. All of the natives are dwarfed by the trees beside them (use of trees), let alone the vast mountains beyond.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials Michaelangelo Used in the Sistine Chapel Frescos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/materials-michaelangelo-used-in-the-sistine-chapel-frescos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/materials-michaelangelo-used-in-the-sistine-chapel-frescos/</guid>
      <description>Pope Julius II commissioned Michaelangelo to paint the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel in 1508. Reluctantly, Michaelangelo accepted and spent four years creating ellaborate frescos on the ceiling with little help. Creating frescos is an ellaborate process. Michaelangelo first applied of a plaster consisting of lime, water, and a volcanic ash onto a surface he prepared the day before. It is believed that he occasionally even put another layer of preperation to brighten the colors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plants in Manet&#39;s Painting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plants-in-manets-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plants-in-manets-painting/</guid>
      <description>Finer brush strokes used for the people and the still life.&#xA;Plants create depth in the scene&#xA;Plants provide cover&#xA;Pose of the man on the left similar to Adam in The Creation of Adam my Michaelangelo.&#xA;Branches and trunks open up in the back and invite the outside world to look at the bather in the back. She is also clothed in all white, appears very innocent, away from the men, and is next to younger trees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rock Garden Formal Analysis?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rock-garden-formal-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rock-garden-formal-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Rock garden at the Bronx Botanical garden&#xA;Gardens are certainly art. We consider the back area in the rock garden of the New York Botanical Garden.&#xA;Gardens as art.&#xA;Plants are constantly changing and growing and different in seasons We walk though them and see them at many different angles Lighting constantly changes Analyzing the rock garden in the spring.&#xA;large trees around make for an oasis inside. Water does smth Different plant choices integral Rocks and the path are the only permanent things, they create the structure and shape of the garden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is art?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-is-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-is-art/</guid>
      <description>What is art? While a simple question, it is a controversial topic in modern philosophy. This essay explores difficulties of defining art, and presents various entities that highlight the boundaries of what we consider art.&#xA;Defining art Constraints on the defintions of art Cite describes 10 constraints on definitions of art. We consider INSERT NUMBER of them.&#xA;Traditionally, artworks are intentionally endowed by their makers with properties, often sensory, having a significant degree of aesthetic interest, usually surpassing that of most everyday objects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art Autobiography</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/art-autobiography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/art-autobiography/</guid>
      <description>Main writing My grandmother on my mother&amp;rsquo;s side has been the only person in my family who regularly creates artwork that fit in a frame. She has most commonly created landscapes of temperate forests with large mountains in the distance, occasionally featuring small, old European structures. While she has explored mediums like oil painting, she mainly does cross-stitching. She has used books for reference and gone from her own imagination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bear</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Bear Website: https://bearblog.dev&#xA;There is a website obesity crisis. Bloated websites are full of scripts, ads, and trackers slowing your readers down every time they try to read your well-crafted content.&#xA;Bear is all you need to build a fantastic and optimized site or blog. It works perfectly on any viewing device. All you need to focus on is writing good content.&#xA;Bear makes it simple to publish content online and grow an audience while keeping pages tiny, fast, and optimized for search engines.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
