<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nature and Art</title>
    <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nature and Art</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024, Beach Ogden.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bob Ross in Art History</title>
      <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/bob-ross-in-art-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/bob-ross-in-art-history/</guid>
      <description>The syllabus of Masterpieces of Western Art at Columbia ignores one of the most famous modern painters, Bob Ross. In this essay, I attempt to insert him into the canon.&#xA;Bob Ross Bob Ross was born in 1942 in Daytona Beach, Florida. He started painting while stationed in Alaska with the US Air Force. He later learned his alla prima, colloquially known as wet-on-wet, oil painting technique from Bill Alexander, host of The Magic of Oil Painting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials Michaelangelo Used in the Sistine Chapel Frescos</title>
      <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/materials-michaelangelo-used-in-the-sistine-chapel-frescos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/materials-michaelangelo-used-in-the-sistine-chapel-frescos/</guid>
      <description>Pope Julius II commissioned Michaelangelo to paint the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel in 1508. Reluctantly, Michaelangelo accepted and spent four years creating ellaborate frescos on the ceiling with little help (Sistine Chapel). Creating frescos is an ellaborate process. Michaelangelo first applied of a plaster consisting of lime, water, and a volcanic ash onto a surface he prepared the day before (Fresco Painting). It is believed that he occasionally even put another layer of preperation to brighten the colors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York Botanical Garden, Rock Garden</title>
      <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/new-york-botanical-garden-rock-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/new-york-botanical-garden-rock-garden/</guid>
      <description>This essay applies artistic formal analysis to gardens, specifically to the Rock Garden in the New York Botanical Garden.&#xA;Analyzing gardens Analyzing gardens presents unique opportunities and difficulties compared to paintings and sculpture. The garden can be viewed from every possible angle, especially from inside. Famous garden designer Piet Oudolf says &amp;ldquo;I can see things that will happen over time.&amp;rdquo; Lighting changes throughout the day, leaves change throughout the seasons, and plants grown and die throughout the years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plants in Manet&#39;s Le Déjeuner sur l&#39;herbe</title>
      <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/plants-in-manets-le-d%C3%A9jeuner-sur-lherbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/plants-in-manets-le-d%C3%A9jeuner-sur-lherbe/</guid>
      <description>Edouard Manet, Le Déjeuner sur l&amp;rsquo;herbe, 1862-63. Oil on canvas. Paris, Musée d’Orsay.&#xA;In class, we analyzed Manet&amp;rsquo;s Le Déjeuner sur l&amp;rsquo;herbe. We mainly focused on the figures, paying little attention to the plants. This essay focuses on the plants, mainly how they emphasize the juxtaposition of the woman in the front and the woman in the back of the painting.&#xA;Edouard Manet, Le Déjeuner sur l&amp;rsquo;herbe, 1862-63. Oil on canvas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rock Mountain Landscape Painting</title>
      <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/rock-mountain-landscape-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/rock-mountain-landscape-painting/</guid>
      <description>Albert Bierstadt, The Rocky Mountains, Lander&amp;rsquo;s Peak, 1863. Oil on canvas. New York, The Metropolitan Museum of Art.&#xA;Bierstadt&amp;rsquo;s painting depicts Lander&amp;rsquo;s peak in modern day Wyoming. The painting can be divided into three regions, the flat plain at the bottom, the rocky forested terrain in the middle, and the large mountains in the distance.&#xA;Flat plain The bottom depicts the Shoshone Native Americans. Almost everyone is focused on what&amp;rsquo;s in front of them, handling animals they hunted, weaving fabrics, chatting, or riding horses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is art?</title>
      <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/what-is-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/what-is-art/</guid>
      <description>What is art? While a simple question, it is a controversial topic in modern philosophy. This essay explores difficulties in defining art, and presents case studies involving plants to highlight the difficulties. I will raise more questions than I answer.&#xA;Difficulties in defining art Adajian describes ten constraints on definitions of art (Adajian). We focus on three of them.&#xA;Traditionally, artworks are intentionally endowed by their makers with properties, often sensory, having a significant degree of aesthetic interest, usually surpassing that of most everyday objects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art Autobiography</title>
      <link>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/art-autobiography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://berkott.github.io/nature-and-art/art-autobiography/</guid>
      <description>Main writing My grandmother on my mother&amp;rsquo;s side has been the only person in my family who regularly creates artwork that fit in a frame. She has most commonly created landscapes of temperate forests with large mountains in the distance, occasionally featuring small, old European structures. While she has explored mediums like oil painting, she mainly does cross-stitching. She has used books for reference and gone from her own imagination.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
